《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我都说过了嘛
Told you.
小菜一碟
Easy as pie.
-什么  -对不住了  弗兰基
- What? - Sorry, Frankie.
阿诺德・弗拉斯
Arnold Flass.
你因杀害利昂・温克勒被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Leon Winkler.
你真以为这些人会允许你逮捕我吗
You really think these guys are gonna let you arrest me?
闭嘴吧  弗拉斯
Shut up, Flass.
企鹅  过来
Penguin, come here.
你是只聪明的小猴子
You're a smart monkey...
但我是动物园的看守
but and I'm the zookeeper.
我没想到会是你  亲爱的
I didn't think it was going to be you, my dear.
你可以出来了
You can come out now.
你又说对了  我的朋友
Right, as usual, my friend.
你得走了
You got to go!
我起誓  布奇
I swear, Butch,
我会回来杀了企鹅
I'm gonna come back and kill Penguin
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：艾瑞卡   迷失_绽放   Silence   爵士年代蓬蓬裙
翻译：charcie   Reginamoon   哥谭直属   DustD   草草
时间轴：艹明   最可爱的小胖子   Kallen
特效&后期：宝宝          校对&总监：草草
不  求你了
Oh, no, please.
不要  不要  求你了
Don't, don't, please, please!
哥谭
第一季  第十四集
你确定吗
You're sure, now?
菲什・穆尼已经完蛋了
Fish Mooney is done.
她试图扳倒法尔科内
She tried to bring down Falcone.
结果没成
She failed.
上次我见到她时  维克多・萨斯把她逼到绝境了
Last time I saw her, Victor Zsasz had her cornered.
我们可以认定  她现在非死即伤
We can assume she's either dead or extremely unwell.
那好  干杯
Well, then. Salud.
这创造了些有趣的机遇
You know, this creates some intriguing opportunities.
法尔科内会想方设法
Falcone will struggle
留住她的地盘
to hold on to her territories.
要是我们动作够快
If we move quickly...
所见略同
My thinking exactly.
事实上
In fact,
我已自作主张收了她的夜店
I took the liberty of claiming her nightclub.
当然是在您名下
In your name, of course.
是吗
You did, huh?
脑子转挺快
Good thinking.
一鸟在手即为所有
A bird in the hand is nine-tenths of the law, right?
没错  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
老大  找您的
Phone for you, boss.
说
Speak.
你好  萨尔
Hello, Sal.
你听起来很吃惊
You sound surprised.
让我猜猜  你的小伙伴企鹅跟你说我死了
Let me guess-- your little friend Penguin told you I was dead.
与死无异
As good as.
我只是休个假而已
I'm just on a vacation for a while.
我也不准备骗你
I'm not going to lie,
我以为我能胜利  结果  却被耍了
I thought I was gonna end up on top. Instead, I got played.
原来  企鹅自始至终
Turns out, Penguin has been
都是法尔科内的人
Falcone's man the whole time.
他把我们俩都当猴耍了
They played us both for suckers.
是吗
Is that right?
千真万确
Ah, indeed.
在我准备宰了他前  他亲口告诉我的
He told me himself, right before I was about to gut him.
你明白我为什么会有所疑虑
You understand why I might be skeptical,
毕竟告诉我这个消息的人是你
considering it's you telling me this.
醒醒吧  傻瓜
Oh, wake up, dummy.
你难道想说
You mean to tell me
你从来就没怀疑过什么
this whole time you haven't suspected anything?
他就没有一次说漏嘴然后解释敷衍过去了吗
That he hasn't made one slip that he's had to explain away?
或许你其实想相信他的谎言
Or maybe even you wanted to believe his lies.
但还是让人不放心  不是吗
But it still gnaws at you, doesn't it?
那份疑虑
The doubt.
这儿  有个污点
It's right there. A smudge.
下次不许再犯了
Don't let it happen again.
或许有一两次
Maybe a couple of times.
该清理你的手下了  萨尔维多
It's time to get your house in order, Salvatore.
要记得是谁点醒你的
And remember who put you wise.
但愿不是坏消息
Not bad news, I hope.
不  我得北上一趟
Nah. I got to go upstate.
找一个人有点事
See a guy about a thing.
跟我一起来
Come with me.
我们可以好好讨论一下机遇
We can talk about opportunities.
好啊
Sure.
让我先回家一趟
Just, uh, let me run home and...
我们得马上走  就现在
We got to go now. Right now.
好极了
Super.
我最喜欢旅游了
I love a road trip.
哈维
Harvey?
警监
Captain.
什么情况
What have we got?
昨晚某个时刻  那边那位幸运先生
Sometime last night, Mr. Lucky there
被绑在了椅子上  脖子上套了绳索
got tied to that chair, noose was dropped over his neck
然后被从大楼一侧抛了下去
and he's heaved over the side.
今早有几个上班族上来抽烟时发现了尸体
Some suits coming up for a smoke this morning found him.
他怎么回到楼顶的
How'd he get back up to the roof?
瞧那边的滑轮
See that pulley there?
我估计  是凶手捞回来的
My guess, it was the killer.
这家伙费尽心思让死者回到楼顶
Guy went to a lot of trouble to get him back up.
为什么不干脆让他一直吊着呢
Why not just leave him hanging?
早上好  警监
Morning, Captain.
早上好  爱德
Morning, Ed.
你越切割我  我长得越大  我是什么
The more you cut me the bigger I grow. What am I?
我们在楼顶  尼格玛
We're on a rooftop, Nygma.
别逼我
Don't tempt me.
洞孔  我是个洞孔
A hole. I'm a hole.
好吧
Okay.
有什么关联啊
Relevance?
被害人的腹部有个洞孔  是手术切口
There's a hole, a surgical incision in our victim's abdomen.
是死后切开的
Certainly postmortem.
凶手应该是在找东西
Killer was looking for something.
等回到实验室  我再做彻底的尸检
I'll have to examine the body more fully back at the lab.
你是指验尸官会做
You mean the medical examiner will.
不过...
Well, but...
你是鉴证科的  爱德
You handle forensics, Ed.
验尸由戈拉医生负责
The bodies belong to Dr. Guerra.
他已正式投诉数次
And he's made formal complaints.
我无法再为你掩护了
I can't cover for you anymore.
我明白了  长官
I read you, ma'am.
非常清楚
Loud and clear.
戈登去哪了
So where's Gordon?
处理私事  他马上就过来
Personal stuff. He'll be in soon.
别离楼边太近
Hey, don't stand so near the edge.
你担心我吗  警监
You worried about me, Captain?
你知道我中午以后才会开始喝酒
You know I don't start drinking till noon.
你要我跟你挑明吗
I got to spell it out for you?
弗拉斯警探有很多朋友
Detective Flass had a lot of friends,
而你的搭档以凶杀罪逮捕了他
and your partner arrested him for murder.
意外无处不在
Accidents happen.
是你拿手铐铐他的
You put the cuffs on him.
所以我们都要小心
So we should all be careful.
见鬼去吧
To hell with them.
芭芭拉
Barbara?
放开我
Let go of me.
你住多久了
How long you been here?
就昨晚
Just last night.
还有之前几次
And a couple times before.
我知道你女友不在
I knew your girlfriend was gone,
还听说你被派去守疯人院
and I heard you got sent to guard that loony bin,
于是我想  在这儿留宿比睡街上好
so I figured better here than sleeping on the street.
-你看见芭芭拉了吗  -没有
- Have you seen Barbara? - No.
你们俩算彻底完了吗
Oh, so things are over between you two, huh?
你确定你能进来吗
Sure you should be here then?
也许你才是闯入者
Maybe you're the one breaking in.
我是过来放钥匙的  去收拾你的东西
Came by to drop off keys. Go get your stuff.
为什么  你要带我去哪里
Why? Where are you taking me?
你不能住在这里
Well, you're not staying here,
也不能住在街上
and you're not gonna stay on the street.
我给你找个安全的地方
I'll find you someplace safe.
安全
Safe.
像韦恩庄园那样安全吗
Safe like Wayne Manor?
上次你出的好主意
That was your last great idea.
那我就给你找别的地方
So someplace else.
你还是韦恩案唯一的证人
You're still my only witness to the Wayne murders.
布鲁斯回来之后你没跟他说过话吗
You haven't talked to Bruce since he got back?
-没有  怎么了  -因为我告诉过他了
- No. Why? - Because I told him already.
我什么也没看见
I didn't see anything.
我说谎了
I lied.
你女友的事真可惜
Sucks about your girlfriend.
她的东西真有档次
She's got some really nice stuff.
等下
Hey, wait!
站住
Stop!
詹姆斯・戈登警探来见你了  布鲁斯少爷
Detective James Gordon to see you, Master Bruce.
警探
Detective.
布鲁斯  你好吗
Bruce, how are you?
我很好  谢谢
I'm fine, thank you.
我之前就该过来的
I would've come by earlier,
但是最近事情有点乱
but things were a little crazy.
你离开了一阵子
You were gone for a while.
瑞士
Switzerland.
好决定
Probably wise.
我见到了塞琳娜・凯尔
I saw Selina Kyle.
她跟我说她撒谎了
She told me she lied.
她什么都没看到
She saw nothing.
是的
Yes.
她也是这么和我说的
That's what she told me.
她为了不去少管所而编了个故事
She made up the story to get out of juvie.
她现在这么说可能是因为害怕了
She could be saying this now because she's scared.
鉴于之前发生的事  这也可以理解
It would be understandable after what happened.
不
No.
她没有那么胆小
She doesn't scare easily.
我相信她
I believe her.
她没有看到凶手
She didn't see the killer.
这确实很令人遗憾
Look, this is unfortunate,
但是这不意味着我们就回到了起点
but it doesn't mean we're back to square one.
有人派了刺客杀她
Someone sent assassins after her.
只有心怀鬼胎的人才会这么做
Only a guilty person would do that.
是呀  把该死的刺客引来了庄园
Yes, and led her bloody assassins to the manor.
真是太感谢你了
Thank you very much.
总之  你不需要再关注这件案子了
Anyway, you need no longer concern yourself with the case.
布鲁斯  这不是放弃的时候
Bruce, this isn't the time to give up.
我没要放弃
I'm not giving up.
我不明白
I don't understand.
几个月前  你保证你会找到杀害我父母的凶手
Months ago, you promised you'd find who killed my parents,
而这段时间里  你只找到了一名证人
and in all that time, you've managed to find one witness,
还是个假冒的
who turned out to be a liar.
这种调查需要时间
An investigation like this takes time.
我理解  但是我不想让你觉得
I understand, but I don't want you to feel bound
被一个无法实现的诺言所束缚
by an oath you can't fulfill.
你不需要再遵守对我的承诺了
I'm releasing you from your promise.
我会自己追查这件事
I'll pursue the matter on my own.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
劝你别费劲了  真的  老兄
Yeah, no, I really wouldn't bother, actually, mate.
一旦布鲁斯少爷决定了
Once Master Bruce makes up his mind,
就无法再说服他了
there's no arguing with him.
他不能自己追查这件事
He can't pursue this case on his own.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
那我就得照顾他了
Then I'll have to look after him.
我送你去门口吧
Can I show you the door?
瞌睡虫
Hey, sleepy head.
我们到了
We're here.
你闻到这味道了吗
You smell that air?
乡下的味道
That's country air.
咱们去弄点吃的吧
Let's get some chow.
吃的
Chow.
太好了
Excellent.
您那个人呢
So where's the guy?
什么人
Which guy?
有事的那个人
The guy with the thing.
他会来的
Oh, he'll be along.
你不喜欢咖啡吗
You don't like the coffee?
我喜欢咖啡
I like the coffee.
那燕麦粥呢
How about the oatmeal?
也很喜欢
Also delicious.
出城感觉挺不错的吧
It's good to get out of the city, huh?
远离尘嚣  噪音
Away from the fumes, the noise.
终于能静下心思考了
I can finally hear myself think.
这里是那么
It's all so...
简单  干净  诚实
simple and clean and honest out here.
新鲜空气  燕麦粥
Fresh air, oatmeal,
好朋友
good friends.
说得太对了
How true.
在哥谭  咱俩总没时间交流  反思
In Gotham, we never have any time to connect, to reflect.
-你明白吗  -当然
- You feel that? - Absolutely.
这个有事的人
This guy with the thing...
是什么事啊
What is the thing?
别去想那人了
Stop worrying about that guy.
知道我在想什么吗
You know what I was thinking about?
真是疯狂
This is crazy.
印第安山
Indian Hill.
阿卡姆那块我用来跟法尔科内换你脑袋的
You know, that dump in Arkham that I traded to Falcone
破地皮
for your neck.
怎么忘得了呢
How could I forget?
我不胜感激
I'm eternally grateful.
是你在我耳边提议的
You suggested it, whispered it in my ear.
那是块一文不值的破地
It's worthless land.
真的是一文不值吗
But was it so worthless?
法尔科内当时立刻就同意了
I mean, Falcone snapped it up pretty quick.
就是个象征
It was a token.
他只是要挽回面子而已
He simply needed to save face.
在尼古拉死后
After Nikolai died...
我说了你肯定不会信
Ah, see, you wouldn't believe it.
我正好也在想这件事
That's the other thing I was thinking about.
跟尼古拉的那场火拼  弗兰基被杀那次
The fight with Nikolai when Frankie was killed.
他被捅了有十刀吧
What was he stabbed, like, ten times?
我不记得具体数目了
I don't recall the exact number.
但那是场枪战啊
Only, it was a gunfight.
弗兰基怎么会死在一把刀下
How'd Frankie get killed with a knife?
这事一直让我百思不得其解
That always kind of bugged me.
老实说
Honestly,
每当牵涉到武力  我就没多大用了
I'm not much use when things get physical.
很抱歉我没能救他
I'm sorry I couldn't save him.
我只是在回想
I was just reminiscing.
别责怪自己
Don't beat yourself up about it.
我们都有各自的长处
We all got our talents, right?
是的
Yes, we do.
我
Me...
别看块头大  反应其实很敏捷
I'm deceptively quick for a big guy.
没错
Yes, you are.
我要出去呼吸点新鲜空气
I'm gonna go get some air.
等那个有事的人来
Wait for the guy with the thing, hmm?
那人  没错
The guy. Right.
不如第一次就别出错
How about getting it right the first time
这样我们就不用总这样了
so we don't have to keep doing this?
布洛克警探
Detective Bullock?
正是  有话快说
It's my name. Don't wear it out.
我叫斯科蒂・穆伦斯
I'm Scottie Mullens.
你找我谈亚当・戈多夫斯基的事
You called me about Adam Jodowsky.
对  穆伦斯小姐  没错
Oh... Oh, Miss Mullens, yes.
谢谢你来一趟
Thank you for stopping by.
小姐还是夫人
Uh, Miss? Mrs.?
小姐
Miss.
好的  好的  这边请
Good. Good. Please.
那
So...
你是怎么认识戈多夫斯基先生的
how did you know Mr. Jodowsky?
我是他的担保人
I was his sponsor, sort of.
我们一起参加互助组
We're... we're in a support group together.
他死了  是吗
He's dead, isn't he?
你为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
这里是凶案组
This is a homicide division.
而你是凶案组警探
You're a homicide detective.
今早我们发现了他的尸体
We found his body this morning.
他的口袋里有你的号码
Your number was in his pocket.
我刚刚给他的
I'd just given it to him.
我最近才开始做他的担保人
I recently started being his sponsor.
这个互助组是什么样的小组
So, uh, what kind of group is this?
是戒酒还是戒毒的
Uh, for booze, pills?
是为患有恐惧症的人而开设的
It's for people suffering from phobias.
-开玩笑吧  -恐惧会让人无力
- You're joking. - Fear can be debilitating.
和人聊聊病情有所帮助
It helps to talk to someone about it.
别犯浑
Don't be an ass.
-你说什么  -你要拿这事开玩笑
- Excuse me? - You were about to make fun.
别犯浑
Don't be an ass.
你说得对  抱歉  我不该这样
You're right. I'm sorry. I was.
不拿这事开玩笑  请坐
No fun-making. Please.
戈多夫斯基先生生前恐惧什么
What was Mr. Jodowsky's phobia?
恐高
Heights.
那如果他被人挂在一座高层建筑上...
So if he was found dangling from the top of a tall building...
天啊  他就是那么...
Oh, my God. Is that how he...?
我需要所有互助组成员的名字
I'm gonna need the names of all the people in the support group.
互助组完全是匿名的
It's completely anonymous.
亚当是唯一一个和我有私交的人
Adam was the only one I knew personally.
不会是互助组里的人干的吧
You don't think someone from the group did this?
有可能  凶手显然知道他的恐惧症
Could be. Killer certainly seemed to know of his phobia.
你是爱尔兰人吗
Are you Irish?
你看着好像是爱尔兰人
Y-You seem like you could be Irish.
这有什么关系
What's it to you?
我只是好奇
I'm just curious.
下一次开会是什么时候
When's the next meeting?
今晚6点
Tonight, 6:00.
一般开多久  一小时吗
And these things-- they usually run, what, an hour?
那么
So,
结束之后  你还可以去吃晚餐
you could maybe go to dinner afterwards.
有这种可能吧
Hypothetically.
有这种可能
很好  我会继续调查这件案子
Okay, well, I'm gonna keep working the case,
如果有必要去互助组走一趟  我会给你打电话的
and I'm gonna call you if I feel the need to go to this meeting.
我们会找到凶手的
We're gonna find who did this.
我保证  穆伦斯小姐
I promise, Miss Mullens.
好的
Okay.
我查了犯罪现场的东西
So I went through the materials from the scene.
绳子和滑轮哪里都买得到
Ropes and pulleys can be bought anywhere.
不管怎么样  我又查了
For what it's worth, I, uh, traced the chair
绑着被害人的椅子
the victim was tied to.
我在听呢
Yeah. I'm listening.
这种木质的滑轮椅是奈何岛
Banker's chair, wooden, made by some company in the Narrows
一家倒闭多年的工厂生产的
that's been closed down for years.
太好了  我们走
Great. Let's go.
真的吗  这条线索希望不大啊  哈维
You sure? That's a pretty thin lead, Harv.
你不是从来不怕麻烦的吗
Since when have you been scared of a little work, huh?
他想要什么呢
What was he after?
啊呀呀
Well, now.
看见了吧  我说了
There! See? I told you!
上帝啊
Oh, dear.
把你的手从尸体里拿出来
Get your hand out of that corpse.
马上
Now.
我刚刚路过
I was just passing by, and I, um,
有点好奇
uh... I was... I was just curious.
我怎么搞的
What was I thinking?
非常抱歉
I... Sorry.
绝不会再这样了  我保证
Won't happen again. Promise.
你要是再不采取行动  我就上报了
Do something about this or I'm going over your head.
我才是法医
I'm the medical examiner!
不是这个胡言乱语的疯子
Not this gibbering loon!
对不起  爱德
I'm sorry, Ed.
你被暂时停职了
Till further notice, you're suspended.
总算啊
Finally.
可我有发现啊
But I found something.
大家都在说
So, word around the house is that
你和美女医生好上了
you and Doc Caliente have a thing.
汤普金斯吗
Thompkins?
算是吧
Yeah, kind of. I guess.
那你和芭芭拉就彻底掰了
So you and Barbara are finally finito?
对
Yeah.
今天去公寓把钥匙留下了
Dropped the keys off at her apartment today.
有没有打分手炮
Get any of that righteous breakup sex?
她不在
She wasn't there.
你发现我从不问你的感情生活吧
You notice I don't ask you about your love life?
我的感情生活短暂凌乱  毫无可瞒
My love life is an open book and a short and nasty one.
不过我看上被害人互助会的那个朋友了
But I'm working on the vic's friend in the phobia support group,
只要她不是凶手
and unless she's the killer,
我一定要追她
I think I'm in there.
这就是我为什么不问
You see why I don't ask?
别伤人家医生的心
Don't screw it up with the doctor.
尽量吧
I'll try not to.
说真的  我最近对你宽宏大量
Seriously, been willing to forgive you on account
都是可怜你欲求不满  可你现在告诉我
of you're not getting laid, but you mean to tell me
这段时间你到处大放厥词
this whole time you've been making speeches,
搞得天翻地覆  居然不是因为寂寞
raising hell, you've had a woman?
一想到你要是寂寞了  能做出什么事来
The thought of what you would do if alone
我就害怕得要死
is truly terrifying.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
把刀子放下
Drop the knife!
怎么回事
What the hell?
还希望不大呢
Thin lead, huh?
进来吧
Come in.
希望一切都合您心意  夫人
I hope everything is to your satisfaction, ma'am.
我很满意  谢谢你  船长
It is. Thank you, Captain.
假如您想道别的话
You can see Gotham on the horizon
可以在地平线上看到哥谭
if you want to say good-bye.
不需要
No need.
我很快就会回来的
I'll be back soon enough.
那么...
Well...
假如您有任何需要  请告诉我
if you need anything, just let me know.
我会的
I will.
这个幸运儿和之前那个死者
This lucky fellow and the previous victim
都在同一个恐惧症互助组
are both part of the same phobia support group.
怕猪吗  难以想象
Pigs. Go figure.
他怎样了
How is he?
现在在哥谭总院  被吓掉了半条命
He's at Gotham General, scared half to death.
医生得给他注射镇定剂
The medics had to sedate him.
你射杀的那个人  他也是互助组的吗
The man you shot-- was he in this group, too?
不是  目前还没查到身份
Nope. No I.D. as yet.
我们在查他的指纹
We're running his prints.
他就是我们要找的人吗  或者另有其人
So is he our man or are we still looking for someone else?
-难说  -就是他了
- Hard to say. - He's our man.
这种怪人一般都是单干的
These sort of wackos work alone.
我要去趟互助组
I'm gonna run by the support group,
告诉他们已经解决了
tell them it's been settled.
我们还不能确定
Hey, we don't know that yet.
你得乐观点
You need to be more optimistic.
的确  你是得乐观点
You do. You need to be more optimistic.
我们抓到了一个罪犯
We have a perp.
第一个死者的死后切口很奇怪
The postmortem incision on the first victim is weird.
凶手在寻找什么  我想弄清楚
The killer was after something. I want to know what.
我要叫尼格玛去看看
I'm gonna ask Nygma to take a look.
不行  他被停职了
No. He's been suspended.
你只能从法医那里拿报告
You got the report from the M.E.
就那个告诉我之前那个证人是从背后
The same M.E. who said my last witness stabbed himself
用冰锥捅死自己的法医吗
to death in the back with an ice pick?
不要  谢了  尼格玛...
No. No, thanks. Nygma...
不是法医
Is not the medical examiner.
我也喜欢他
I like him, too.
但是以目前的状况  我无能为力
But there's nothing I can do, not with the way things are.
什么意思
What do you mean?
听着  我很高兴我们拿下了弗拉斯
Look, I'm glad we took down Flass,
但是有的人是可以查的  有的人则不能
but there are people you go after and people you don't.
所以  现在我们的一举一动都被盯着
So now everything we do is being watched.
你已经抓到坏人了  放手吧
You got the bad guy. Let it go.
很抱歉您被卷入了这件事
I'm sorry you got dragged into it.
不必感到抱歉
Don't be.
那感觉挺好的
Felt good.
是吧
Did, didn't it?
柯林格小姐  我来告诉你我...
Miss Kringle, I came to tell you that I...
你是在哭吗
Have you been crying?
没  没有  我没事
No, no. I'm-I'm fine.
但是我能看见你脸上有眼泪
But I can see tears on your face.
是因为你的朋友弗拉斯警探被捕了吗
Is it because your friend Detective Flass was arrested?
你需要什么  尼格玛先生
What do you need, Mr. Nygma?
对了
Yes.
我被停职了  以后都见不到你了
I've been suspended and won't be seeing you anymore.
所以我想把这支铅笔还给你
So I wanted to return this pencil.
之前我从你办公室拿的
I took it from your office some time ago.
我一直想还给你的
I kept meaning to return it.
现在短了一些
Used to be longer.
你是个怪人  尼格玛先生
You're an odd man, Mr. Nygma.
但是我对你被停职一事深表遗憾
But I'm sorry that you've been suspended.
真希望有办法挽回
I wish something could be done.
坐吧  我们得谈谈
Have a seat. We got to talk.
我觉得我们现在
I feel that the time has come in our relationship
该相互信任了
when we should have trust with each other.
真正的信任
Real trust.
完全坦诚相待
Total honesty between us.
没有秘密
No secrets.
我百分百同意
I 100% agree.
我先说个秘密
So here's a secret to start off.
根本没什么有事的人  我说了谎
There is no guy with a thing. I lied.
我就觉得奇怪呢
I was beginning to wonder about him.
到你了
Now you.
-我  -既然要坦诚
- Me? - We're being honest.
你也要说个秘密作交换
You have to tell me a secret in return.
对您隐瞒的秘密  马罗尼阁下
Secrets from you, Don Maroni?
我没有
I have none.
说吧
Please.
说实话  我不太喜欢吃燕麦
Honestly... I don't really like oatmeal.
知道了
Good to know.
我喜欢这个游戏
See, I like this game.
我再告诉你个秘密
I'll tell you another secret.
菲什・穆尼还活着
Fish Mooney's alive.
我跟她通过话
I spoke to her.
这秘密劲爆吧
Good secret, huh?
菲什都说什么了
What did Fish say?
不
Oh, no.
你得先还我个秘密
You have to tell me a secret first.
得这么玩
That's how it works.
我也不太喜欢喝咖啡
I don't much like coffee either.
好吧
Fair enough.
菲什都说了什么
What did Fish say?
说你和法尔科内一直联手合作
Said you and Falcone have been working together all this time.
她说我认识你的第一天开始
She said you've been playing me for a chump
你就把我当白痴一样耍
since the first day I met you.
她当然会这样说  对不对
She would say that, wouldn't she?
贱人
The bitch.
您不会相信她吧
You don't believe her, do you?
我不得不说
Well, she did put some incidents
这让人用一种全新而不安的眼光看待很多事
in a different and troubling light, I must say.
那真糟糕
Well, that's too bad.
到你了
Your turn.
再说个秘密吧
Tell me another secret.
这次要个劲爆的
A good one this time.
我拿了你的枪
I took your gun.
就在这儿
I have it right here.
这个够劲爆
That's a good secret.
我拿走它是因为我已经猜到穆尼找到了你
I took it because I figured Mooney had called you somehow.
我就知道你会相信她
I knew you might believe her.
但她说的未必是真话
Doesn't mean she's telling the truth.
是吗
Is she?
你有把我当白痴耍吗  企鹅
Have you been playing me for a chump, Penguin?
轮到你说秘密了
I think it's your turn to tell a secret.
你个小杂种
You little dirtbag.
我当你像朋友一样
I treated you like a friend.
猴子朋友吧
Like a monkey friend.
你是动物园看守  记得吗
You're the zookeeper, remember?
说秘密吧
Tell me a secret now.
那再说一个
Just one more then.
这游戏我玩腻了
I'm tired of this game.
这把枪装的是空弹
That gun is loaded with blanks.
骗子
Liar.
-你  -没错
- You... - Yeah.
劲爆吧
Good secret, huh?
感谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
很高兴接到你的电话
I was glad to get your call.
阿卡姆还好吗
How are things at Arkham?
你走后就无聊多了
Little less interesting since you've left.
警局还好吧
How are things at the precinct?
其实我就是因为这个想找你帮忙呢
Um, well, actually, that was what I was hoping you could help me with.
我们接到一个案子
Um, we've got this case,
我想不通凶手到底想怎么样
and I can't understand what exactly our perp was doing.
法医又不太靠谱
And our medical examiner is kind of a clown.
有问题吗
Uh, something wrong?
没  没有
No, not at all.
只是  上次见面时  你很热情
Only, last time we met, you were very passionate.
你打给我的时候  我以为...
So when you called me, I thought...
怎么说呢
Well, whatever.
我涂了口红
I put on lipstick.
而你想要鉴证建议
And you want forensic advice.
你把我搞糊涂了
You're very confusing.
我不是故意的
I don't mean to be. Uh...
案子只是借口
Case is a pretext.
我想见你
I wanted to see you.
为什么不直接说
Why didn't you just say that?
是该这样  不过我很久没这么做过了
I should have. I haven't done this in a while.
有些生疏了
I'm a little rusty.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧
All right.
很好
Well, good.
我可不想涂上口红却会错了意
I don't like to put on lipstick by mistake.
是什么事
So what's the issue?
不不不  别管那案子了
Uh, no, no, no, forget the case.
-不用操心  -没事
- Don't worry. - Please.
我很感兴趣
I'm interested.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
戈登
Gordon.
什么时候
When?
好的  好的
Uh, yeah, okay.
给他录口供  我马上就到
Take his statement. I'll be right there.
很抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry, I have to go.
没事
I'm fine.
-你确定吗  -是的
- You sure? - Yes.
我会把文件拿给你的
I'll bring this back to you.
我是哈维
It's Harvey.
哈维  第二个受害人醒来了
Harvey, second victim woke up.
他说他是被两个人绑架的
Says he was abducted by two men.
还有人逍遥法外
There's someone still out there.
谢谢你过来告诉我们发生的一切
It's kind of you to come here and tell us what happened.
别客气
No problem.
我只是不想让你担心
I just didn't want you worrying, so...
说实话  我觉得你并不像胆小的人
To be honest, you don't strike me as the fraidy cat type.
恐惧症患者不是胆小鬼
Phobics are not fraidy cats.
我知道  只是你看起来很坚强
I know. It's just, you seem like a strong lady is all.
我是很坚强
I am strong.
我只是碰巧害怕游泳池而已
I just happen to be terrified of swimming pools.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
这的确是个问题
Well, I can see how that might be a thing.
几乎人人都有问题
Nearly everyone has a thing.
我敢说  如果你深入内心
I'm sure that you, if you dig deep enough,
也会有需要面对的问题
would have issues that you need to confront.
我是警察  唯一怕的就是低因咖啡
I'm a cop; the only thing I'm scared of is decaf coffee.
真的吗  我发现
Really? I've always found
最优秀最勇敢的人
that the best and bravest people are the ones
往往会坦然承认他们的恐惧
that willingly acknowledge their fears.
也许只是你约会过的人里
Maybe you've just been hanging out
有太多胆小  爱抱怨的人
with too many timid and whiny people.
你真是太坏了
You are so bad.
我总是在害怕
I'm scared all the time.
我愿意
And it's something I'd be
和小组进行分享
willing to share with the group
如果你觉得能对我有帮助的话
if you think it might be helpful.
当然
Yes.
当然  谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
我觉得会有帮助的
I think it would.
第一次
First time?
是的  你呢
Yeah. You?
不是  我一直参加的
No, I'm a regular.
情况是这样的
So here's the deal.
你进到车里
You go in the car,
那辆车已经在粉碎机上了
the car's already in the crusher,
你会被挤压致死
you get squeezed to death,
会用上几分钟才能断气
it takes a couple of minutes to die.
不管出来的是什么  我都会送给法尔科内
Whatever comes out, I send to Falcone.
也许他会拿去做咖啡桌
Maybe he uses it as a coffee table.
马罗尼阁下  请听我说
Don Maroni, please listen to me.
到乞求的部分了吗
Oh, this is the begging part?
很好  因为这是我最爱的部分
Oh, good, 'cause this is my favorite part.
来吧  为你的狗命乞求吧
Go ahead and beg for your miserable life.
容我提议一些选择
Just allow me to suggest some options here.
我死了就毫无价值了
Dead, I'm worthless.
再考虑到法尔科内必然会为此做出报复
If you factor in Falcone's inevitable retaliation,
杀我对您只有损失
killing me will be a net loss for you.
这不是个生意问题
This is not a business issue.
我和弗兰基・卡彭是20多年的朋友了
Me and Frankie Carbone go back 20 years.
你伤了我  企鹅
You hurt me, Penguin.
印第安山的事被您说着了
You were right about Indian Hill.
的确有内幕
There's more to it.
法尔科内知道些内情
Falcone knows something.
我还不知道是什么  但我会查明...
I don't know what, b-but I-I can find out...
够了
Stop it.
我看你都难受
You're making me sad.
我当初怎么就信了你的一派胡言
How did I ever fall for your crap?
不不
N-No.
不要啊
No. No. No.
求您  求您
Please. Please.
不要
No. No.
替我跟弗兰基问个好
Say hi to Frankie for me.
我每天都感到害怕
I'm afraid every day.
我怕自己会死在暗巷里
I'm afraid I'm gonna die in an alley.
慢慢流血至死  而有个人渣却在翻我兜
Bleeding out while some scumbag goes through my pockets
嘲笑我
and laughs at me.
我想说话  却说不出声
And I try to speak, but nothing comes out.
我躺在那里
And I just lie there,
盯着头顶建筑物之间的一小片天空
staring at a small space of sky between the buildings.
然后死去
And then I die.
独自一人
Alone.
我不想独自死在什么破地方
I don't want to die alone in some gutter.
我想死在温暖的床上
I want to die in a warm cozy bed
在一个漂亮女人的怀里
in the arms of a beautiful woman.
多谢分享  哈维
Thank you for sharing, Harvey.
还有别人想分享的吗
Would anyone else like to share?
托德  说吧
Tod, go ahead.
我叫托德
My name is Tod, and...
我以前从未在这里发过言
I've never spoken here before, but...
我特别害怕失败
...I have a horrible terror of failure.
我折磨自己和身边的人
I torment myself and those around me.
为了不失败  我宁可爬碎玻璃
I'd crawl on broken glass to avoid failing.
我愿做任何事
About anything.
这种疾病我是从父亲那里继承来的
I inherited this illness from my father,
但恐怕我如今把它传给了儿子
but I'm afraid I'm passing it on to my son.
有我们呢  托德
We're here for you, Tod.
我昨天下班回家
When I came home from work yesterday,
我的宝贝儿子在哭
my precious son was crying,
他对我说  他...
and he said to me that he...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我说不出口
I can't speak.
-很抱歉  -托德
- I'm so sorry. - Tod?
托德
Tod.
Tod?
开什么玩笑  干什么
Oh, you got to be kidding me. What?
马罗尼阁下  您得听我说
Don Maroni, you have to listen to me.
不
Uh, see, no.
这一切就是这么开始的
This is how this all began,
我听你说话
me listening to you.
我说的是实话
I was telling the truth.
关于印第安山  关于阿卡姆
About Indian Hill. And Arkham.
控制了阿卡姆的人将控制哥谭  我可以...
Whoever controls Arkham will control Gotham! I can...
闭上嘴  像个男人一样死吧
Would you shut up and take it like a man?
达夫废车场
你好  是达夫先生吗
Hello, is this Mr. Duffy?
仔细听好了
Listen to me very carefully.
我就是你这台残暴机器碾压的车里的人
I'm the man in the car in this ferocious machine of yours.
我名叫奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
My name is Oswald Cobblepot.
我为哥谭市的卡麦・法尔科内阁下工作
And I work for Don Carmine Falcone of Gotham City.
你知道法尔科内阁下是谁吗
Do you know who Don Falcone is?
很好  我刚刚给法尔科内阁下打了电话
Good. I just called Don Falcone,
把我在哪和现在的情况都如实告诉了他
and I told him exactly where I am and what's happening.
所以  达夫  你最好赶紧把机器停下
So, Duffy, you better stop this machine right now,
因为如果我死了
because if I die,
法尔科内阁下会派一队人马来
Don Falcone is gonna send a team up here
把你活活剥皮  再杀了你家人
to skin you alive and slaughter your family.
但是马罗尼阁下说
But Don Maroni said...
法尔科内阁下才掌管哥谭
Don Falcone runs Gotham,
你就要杀掉他的得力手下了
and you're about to murder his right-hand man.
搞什么
What the hell?
给我回来
Get back here!
该死的
Son of a bitch.
只有我觉得他俩已经去很久了吗
Is it just me, or have those two been gone a while?
这经历很真实很有趣  但我得走了
This has been real and fun, but I got to go.
天呐
Oh, my God.
不是看上去那样的
This isn't what it looks like.
其他成员说绑架者上个月一直有参与会议
Other members say our abductor's been coming the last month.
自称名字是托德
Said his name was Tod,
但根据互助组规定  他们是匿名的
but group protocol requires they remain anonymous.
所以查不到真实身份
So no real I.D.
你打中的那个  那个猪人呢
And the guy you shot, the one with the pigs?
指纹结果出来了  是职业罪犯
Prints came back: career criminal.
大概只是动手的  说了算的是另一个
Probably just the muscle. The other guy was in charge.
他知道会议上有个警察
He knew there was a cop there at the meeting.
还是劫走了她
He still took her.
这不是冷酷就是疯狂
That's cold or crazy.
不管怎样  他一定会采取同样的犯罪手法
Either way, he's almost sure to follow the same M.O.
他会逼穆伦斯小姐面对最大的恐惧
He'll confront Miss Mullens with her greatest fear.
就是溺水
Which is drowning.
准确说是在泳池里
Specifically in a pool.
哥谭有几百个泳池呢
There's hundreds of pools in Gotham.
-我们不可能每个都顾及到  -她妈妈的电话
- We can't possibly get to every... - That was her mother.
斯科蒂7岁的时候差点淹死在
When she was seven, Scottie almost drowned
上城区的拉马斯公园游泳池
in Lemmars Park pool uptown.
这是个起点吧
It's a start, I guess.
他一定是带她去那儿了  我能感觉到
That's where he took her, I can feel it.
-老大  -不是时候  乔
- Boss? - Uh, not now, Joe.
等等
Wait.
那不是我想的那样吧
Tell me that's not what it looks like.
你很勇敢
You're brave.
能给你个8分了
I'd say you're an eight on the Crane Scale.
深度恐惧
Profound fear.
12分是满分
12 is top.
令心脏停跳的深刻恐惧
Abject heart-stopping terror.
你只有8真是令我惊讶
I'm surprised you're only an eight.
你明白这事是真的在发生吧
You do understand that this is really happening?
我要淹死你
I'm going to drown you.
就现在
Right now.
好了  到10了
There! That's a ten.
爸爸
Dad.
乔纳森  我叫你在车里等的
, I said to wait in the van.
停车计时器到时间了
The parking meter ran out.
儿子  我知道这很艰难
Look, son, I know this hard,
但我们谈过了
but we talked about it.
这是为了大局  为了人类
It's for the common good, for humanity.
我知道  我只是...我觉得...
I know. I just... I think...
很快就好了  给
This will be over soon. Here.
去投到计时器里
Go and feed the meter.
去吧
Go on, go.
亲爱的  别太怪我
Now, my dear, don't think badly of me.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
别动
Don't move!
我追他  你救她
I'm on him! You get her!
他还活着
He's alive.
我就说他还活着
I told you he was alive.
感谢主
Praise the Lord.
我主仁慈
Glory be.
你是怎么了  孩子
What happened to you, boy?
就如浪子  女士  我堕落了
Like the prodigal son, ma'am, I have fallen.
就像约伯  我被投入最深的不忠深渊
Like Job, I've been tested in the deepest pits
接受试炼  而存活了下来
of the devil's perfidy and survived.
吾主仁慈
Lord have mercy.
你们不会是要去哥谭市吧
Are you headed to Gotham City, by any chance?
是啊  来吧
Sure. Come on.
这是你给我的那个被从楼上扔下去的男人的案卷
Case files you gave me about that man who was thrown from the roof.
你抓到凶手了吗
Did you catch his killer yet?
还没  他还在逃
Uh, no. He's still out there.
我跟踪调查了一下
I followed up,
然后给他做了个尸检
and I had a quick look at his corpse.
你还尸检了
A quick look at his corpse?
就在楼下停尸间里  没什么麻烦的
Yeah, its' just downstairs at the morgue. No trouble.
凶手取走了他的肾上腺
So the killer removed his adrenal glands.
肾上腺  真奇怪
Adrenal glands? That's strange.
这东西在黑市上没有价值吧
They have no value on the black market, do they?
没有  肾和肝脏  有
No. Kidneys and livers, yes.
肾上腺  没有
Adrenal glands, no.
它产生皮质醇
It produces cortisol,
这种激素激发我们的战斗-逃逸反应
the hormone that gives us that adrenalized fight-or-flight reaction.
总之  就是恐惧腺
Essentially, it's the fear gland.
而凶手要在被害人最害怕的时候
And our man wants to take it from the victim
取走他的肾上腺  为什么呢
when he's most fearful. Why do that?
我只能想到  在死亡来临的时刻
All I can think of is that at the moment of death,
被害人的肾上腺能产生
the victim's adrenals would produce a massive,
大量高质的皮质醇
highly-elevated form of cortisol.
很有意思吧
Fascinating, huh?
这人真怪
This is one weird dude.
应该是个医生或护士
A doctor or a nurse, most likely.
他们能把肾上腺切除得那么干净是需要技术的
Takes some skill to remove adrenals as cleanly as they did.
你真的很喜欢这种工作  是吧
You really like this kind of work, huh?
是啊
I do.
很好
Good.
或许今后还有更多机会
Maybe there'll be more for you.
甚至是全职工作
A full-time job, even.
我们的法医因盗取尸块被开除了
Our M.E. has been fired for stealing body parts.
能相信吗
Can you believe that?
在哥谭就不奇怪
Only in Gotham.
我们回头谈谈这份可能的工作
So, what do you say we discuss this potential job
一起吃个晚饭吧
over dinner?
说的真圆滑啊
Nice segue, Mr. Smooth.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚饭是个好主意
Dinner sounds good.
你还要带上卷宗吗
Are you gonna bring your case files?
随你嘲笑我生疏的约会技能吧
Go ahead, mock my crude dating skills.
我已经尽力了
I'm doing my best.
你挺好的
You're doing fine.
我现在好想吻你
I have a powerful urge to kiss you right now.
为什么不呢
Why don't you?
因为我在当班
Because I'm on duty, and, uh...
而且有50来个人在看着我们呢
there's about 50 people watching us.
害怕了
Scaredy-cat.
当然  我还得维护形象呢
Damn straight. I have an image to keep up.
无情  刻板的硬汉吗
The heartless, by-the-book, hard man.
算是吧
Kind of.
数到三  我就靠过来
On the count of three, I'm gonna lean in,
这样就很自然了
so that it's subtle.
你得吻我的脸颊  否则就别想吃饭了
Then you're gonna kiss me on the cheek or no dinner.
-别这样  -我认真的
- Come on. - I'm serious.
一
One,
二
two,
三
three.
我不用走了
I'm not leaving after all.
什么
What?
验尸官要走人了
It turns out that the medical examiner is leaving,
所以艾森警监复了我的职
so Captain Essen decided to reinstate me.
好啊
Okay, good.
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma?
你欠我一只新铅笔
You owe me a new pencil.
怎么了  怎么回事
What's going on? What's happening?
我可以把你藏起来  快来
I can hide you. Quickly.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com